Guide to the Frederick Emmons Terman Papers SC0160
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Stanford Administration, 1948-1972; Series III
  - PROVOST'S PERSONAL PAPERS
    - SRI: Board of Directors. July-Dec. 1960. (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - SRI: Board of Directors. Jan.-May 1961. (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - SRI: Board of Directors. June-Dec. 1961. (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - SRI: Board of Directors. Jan.-July 1962. (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - SRI: Board of Directors. Aug.-Dec. 1962. (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - SRI: Board of Directors. 1963. (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - SRI: Board of Directors. 1964 - 66. (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - SRI Board of Directors: Minutes. 1960 - 61. (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - SRI Board of Directors: Minutes. 1962 - 63. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - SRI Board of Directors: Minutes. 1964 - 65. (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - SRI - Computers. 1962 - 65. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - SRI - Demonstrations. 1968 - 69. (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - SRI - Draper Committee. 1965. (special committee chaired by William Draper to examine Institute's objectives) (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - SRI - Executive Committee. 1960 - 63. (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - SRI - Executive Committee. 1964 - 65. (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - SRI - Executive Committee - memos and notes. 1964 65. (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - SRI - Executive Committee - reports to Exec. Com. 1965. (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - SRI - Finance Committee. 1961 - 62. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - SRI - Financial Statements. 1961 - 65. (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - SRI - Folkers, Carl. 1964 - 65. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - SRI - Fund raising. 1964 - 65. (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - SRI Grant. (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - SRI - New Associates Plan. 1965. (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - SRI - Packard, David - material for. 1965 - 66. (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - SRI - Personnel Committee. 1961 62. (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - SRI - Research Committee. 1961. (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - SRI - Scientist's Search. 1961 62 (Search for SRI Director). (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - SRI - Stanford Relations. 1961 65. (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - SRI - Stanford Committee. 1963 65. (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - SRI - Stanford (Weldon Gibson). (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - SRI - Stanford Joint Committee - Reports. 1965. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - SRI - Miscellaneous Problems. 1962 - 65. (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - SRI - Miscellaneous Publications and Responses. 1964 - 66. (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Statistics, Department of. 1951 - 64. (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Statler Hotel Project. 1958. (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Steere, William. 1957 - 58. (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Student Financial Aid. 1957 - 60. (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Student Financial Aid. 1961 - 65. (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Student Housing. 1960 - 61. (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Student Problems - Stanford and Berkeley. 1964 - 65. (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Student Problems - Stanford and Berkeley. 1966 - 67. (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Summer Festival. 1963 65. (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Summer Session. 1956 59. (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Summer Session. 1960 65. (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Suppes, Patrick. 1965. (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Supplementary Compensation, Committee on. 1957 64. (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - T TI. (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - TO TZ (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Tarr, Curtis. 1960 - 72. (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Tenure Policy. 1959 - 63. (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Tenure Policy. 1964 - 65. (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Terman - Meetings with departments guidelines. 1956 - 57. (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Texaco. 1960. (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Trustees, Board of. 1956 - 61. (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Trustees, Board of. 1962 - 65. (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Tuition rates - information. 1960 74. (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - U (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Undergraduate Education. 1961 - 63. (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Undergraduate Education. 1964 - 65. (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Undergraduate Instruction. May-Sept. 1962 (History Department experiment) (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Undergraduate Residence Program. 1964 - 69. (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Union Negotiations. 1964. (re Hansen Labs, SEL and SLAC) (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - United States Office of Education. 1964 - 69. (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Universities Research Association. 1965 - 66. (re 200 bev National Accelerator) (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - University Distinguished Professorships. 1957 59. (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - University Relations. 1960 - 65. (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - V (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Varian - Fellowship and General Correspondence. 1956 - 65. (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Vice-Presidents' Meetings. 1959 - 64. (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Villard, Oswald G., Jr. 1963 - 66. (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Visiting Committees at Stanford. 1960 - 63. (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Visiting Committees: Harvard, MIT, Princeton. 1959 - 60. (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Visitors at Stanford. 1958 - 71. (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - W WE (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - WH WZ (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Weissbluth, Mitchell. 1962 - 63. (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Wert, Robert. 1958 - 67. (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Whitaker, Douglas. 1956. (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Whitaker, Virgil. 1963 - 71. (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Wickizes, Vernon. 1955 - 63. (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman. 1972. (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - William, Prince of Gloucester. 1963 - 65. (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Women. 1958 - 62. (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Women's Physical Education. 1956 - 57. (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Woodrow Wilson Fellowships. 1958 - 67. (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - X-Y-Z. (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Yale. 1960 - 65. (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - PROVOST'S STAFF MEETINGS
    Contains minutes, agendas and supporting documents (memoranda) -arranged chronologically by meeting. For each meeting the agenda is filed first, followed by various attachments-relevant to meeting, and finally the minutes of the meeting. The supporting documents are not necessarily filed chronologically, but instead in the order in which they were attached to agenda.
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. Sept.-Dec. 1959. (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. Jan.-June 1960. (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. Sept.-Dec. 1960. (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. Jan.-July 1961. (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. Sept. 1961-April 1962. (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. May-June 1962. (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. Sept.-Dec. 1962. (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. Jan.-June 1963. (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. Dec. 1963-March 1964. (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. April-June 1964. (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. Nov. 1964-Feb. 1965. (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Provost's Staff Meetings: Minutes, agenda, memoranda. March-August 1965. (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Provost's appointment calendar. 1959 - 60. (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Provost's appointment calendar. 1960 - 61. (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Provost's appointment calendar. 1961 -62. (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Provost's appointment calendar. 1962 -63. (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Provost's appointment calendar. 1963 -64. (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Provost's appointment calendar. 1964 -65. (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - STUDIES FOR STERLING
    - Control of Faculty Size (Faculty Planning)
      - Faculty Planning Program Report. 1966 - 68. Memoranda requesting Study and Comments on results. Text of report by F. E. Terman, Oct. 1967. (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Data on faculty appointments: Harvard, MIT, Yale, Princeton, UCB - 1957-59; 1967-69. (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Data on faculty appointments at Stanford. 1955 - 67. -Statistics on faculty growth; student enrollment. -Miscellaneous tabulations: NAS summary; age distribution. -FET's tabulations of anticipated faculty retirements. 1967-2007. (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Faculty Planning: 1969 follow-up report. -Statistics. -Drafts of 2 reports: "Higher education is a highly competitive business," and "Faculty planning." (according to note by Terman, study was never fully presented because of interference by student demonstrations) (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Fringe Benefits Study. (Box 64)
      - Fringe Benefits - general. 1967 - 60. (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Medical Clinic Plan. 1966. (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Retirement Study. (Box 64)
      - Retirement Policy - miscellaneous material. 1955 - 65. (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Retirement Policy - approved by Advisory Board. March 1959. (Box 64, Folder 8)
      - Supplementary Pension Program. 1966 - 67. (Box 64, Folder 9)
      - Faculty Retirement Dates: 1964 - 2007 (compiled in 1964 and 1967) (lists by department and by year) (Box 64, Folder 10)
      - Retirement Study: Terman Report, Oct. 17, 1966. (Box 64, Folder 11)
      - Retirement Study: Misc. correspondence. 1966 - 68. (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Retirement Study 1966
      These two large binders contain the data and calculations compiled by Terman on all financial aspects of Stanford faculty retirement.
      - Emeritus lists; information from personnel; TIAA and CREF tables and information; responses to Virgil Anderson's survey of emeritus faculty income. (Box 65, Folder Volume 1)
      - Individual salary and case histories, listed both by year of retirement, and alphabetically. (Box 65, Folder Volume 2)
    - Budgeting Studies (General Fund Ceiling): GSB
      - Request for General Fund Ceiling Study and background materials. Sept.-Nov. 1969. (Requested by President Pitzer through E. Howard Brooks, Vice-Provost) (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - GSB Budget Study: Correspondence and data. 1969 - 71. (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - GSB Budget Study: Working statistics. 1969 - 70. (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - GSB Budget Study: Working materials. Binder containing memoranda, data, and calculations compiled by Terman for General Fund Ceiling Study. (Box 66, Folder Volume 4)
      - GSB Budget Study: Working materials. Binder containing GSB budgets, course consumption, and Controller's tabulations compiled by Terman for Study. (Box 66, Folder Volume 5)
      - Harvard General Fund Ceiling System. May 1970. (Terman's memos on conversations with Harvard administrative officers on their budgeting system.) (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - GSB Budget Study: Final Report, March 10, 1970. (2 copies: one marked by Terman; the other unmarked) (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Budgeting Studies (General Fund Ceiling): Law School 1970.
      - Law School Budget Study: Working materials. Binder containing memoranda, data, and calculations compiled by Terman for study. (Folder 1)
      - Law School Budget Study: Report July 1970. "Applications of General Fund Ceiling Operation to Stanford Law School and Stanford Graduate School of Business: A Comparative Study." (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Budgeting Studies (General Fund Ceiling): Bershader Committee. 1975.
      Biographical/Historical note
      Task force chaired by Dr. Daniel Bershader to review question of budget allocation in other Stanford professional schools.
      - Bershader Committee Materials. 1974 - 75. (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - DATA PROCESSING IN THE PROVOST'S OFFICE (computer print-outs)
    - 1951 - 52. (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - 1955 - 56. (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - 1956 - 57. Computer Print-outs (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - 1957 - 58. (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - 1958 - 59. (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - 1959 -60. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - 1960 -61. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - 1961 -62. Course Enrollment Statistics: Three-Quarter Summary (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - 1962 -63. (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - 1963 -64. (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - 1964 - 65. (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - 1965 - 66. (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - 1966 - 67. (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - 1967 - 68. (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Course Enrollment: by student level. 1956 57. (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Course enrollment: by level; by sex. 1958 59. (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Grade Distribution Report: 1956 - 57; 1960 61; 1962 63 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Grade Distribution: Three-Quarter Summary. 1964 - 65. (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Course enrollment report: By quarter. 1970 - 71. (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Course enrollment report: By quarter. 1974 - 75. (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Courses by Instructor (Box 70)
    - 1955 - 56; 1956 - 57. (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - 1957 - 58; 1958 - 59. (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - 1959 - 60. (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - 1960 - 61. (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - 1961 - 62. (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - 1962 - 63. (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - 1963 - 64. (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - 1964 - 65. (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - 1965 - 66. (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - 1966 - 67. (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - 1967 - 68. (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - 1968 - 69. (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Courses by Instructor: 1969-70. (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Courses by Instructor: 1970 - 71. (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Courses by Instructor: 1971 - 72. (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Summer Session Enrollment: 1955 - 62. (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Summer Session Enrollment: 1962 - 69. (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Staffing: Business, Education, Engineering. Nov. 1967. (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Staffing: Humanities and Sciences. Nov. 1967. (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Staffing: Law, Earth Sciences, Misc. Nov. 1967. (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Staffing: Business, Education, Engineering. July 1968. (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Staffing: Humanities and Sciences. July 1968. (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Staffing: Law, Administration, Biophysics, FRI, misc. July 1978. (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Graduate Financial Aid. 1956 - 57. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Graduate Scholarship Study. Dec. 1957. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Graduate Students: Tuition Fee Analysis. 1958. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Room Utilization. 1956 - 57. (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Salaries. 1956 - 59. (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Salaries. 1961 - 62. (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Report of Department Restricted Funds. Nov. 30, 1957. (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Student Distribution by Major. 1956 - 57. (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Statement of Available Funds as of May 31, 1957. (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Retirement Calculations, Assuming Equities Funds and 15% throughout 1966. (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Tuition Waiver Study (Faculty-Staff Children). Summer 1967. (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - BUDGET WORKING PAPERS
    (binders containing memoranda, data and calculations compiled by Terman to be used in figuring yearly budgets)
    - 1956 - 57. (Box 76, Folder Volume 1)
    - 1957 - 58. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - 1958 - 59. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - 1959 - 60. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - 1960 - 61. (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - 1961 - 62, part I (excludes H. and S. budget materials) (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 1961 - 62 part II (H. and S.) (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - 1962 - 63, part I. (Box 77, Folder Volume 1)
    - 1962 - 63, part II. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - 1963 - 64: Controller's Information. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - 1963 - 64. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - 1964 - 65: Business, Earth Sciences, Education. (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - 1964 - 65: Engineering, H. & S. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - 1964 - 65: Controller's Data; miscellaneous. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 1964 - 65: Allocation; Planning; Graduate Division; Revisions. (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - 1964 - 65: Non-academic; Libraries; Medicine; Reserve. (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Income and Expenditure Forecast 1963 - 66: Assuming Major and Prolonged Economic Decline starting 1962 - 63. 1962. (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Budget History. 1965. (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - MISCELLANEOUS ADMINISTRATIVE FILES
    - Graduate Division Accounts: General and Pending; N.S.F. Institutional Grants. 1964 - 65. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Graduate Division Accounts: NSF Programs; NIH Pre-doctoral Fellowships, 1963 - 65. (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Graduate Division Accounts: NDEA: NASA; Woodrow Wilson. 1963 - 65. (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Graduate Division Accounts: Misc. Academic;Provost's Reserve. 1963 - 65. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Study of Undergraduate Education: F. E. Terman's File. 1955. (grade distribution; percentage of undergraduate units taught by individuals of each rank; study of Freshman English; Report of the Committee on the Course of Study at Yale) (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Study of Undergraduate Education: Terman's File.1955. (Alumni survey; CEEB comparative institutional scores; survey of graduating seniors) (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Study of Undergraduate Education: Terman's File.1955. (Study of variables used to determine freshman admission; CEEB achievement test scores of entering freshmen) (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Presidential Search (Tresidder's successor) - 1948:Faculty Advisory Committee correspondence, Agenda, Minutes, Lists. (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Presidential Search - 1948: Candidate recommendations from Stanford faculty and alumni. (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Presidential Search - 1948: "C" series candidate recommendations (recommendations to be distributed to Faculty Committee only, and not to Trustees Committee) (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Presidential Search - 1948: Solicited recommendations and acknowledgments. (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Presidential Search - 1948: Board of Trustees correspondence and lists. (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Presidential Search - 1948: Lists of Candidates. (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - STATISTICAL DATA (Termans' Personal Files)
    - Direct Instruction Costs Per Student Credit Hour. 1962 - 63; 1968 - 69. 8 binders. (Box 79)
    - Engineering School Statistics. 1962 - 65. 7 binders. Includes one binder on Honors Cooperative Program and one binder on Electrical Engineering. (Box 80)
    - Student Statistics. 1962 - 65. 6 binders. Includes two binders on graduate enrollment; two binders on Ph.D. output per faculty member; one on financial aid; one on NSF fellowships. (Box 81)
    - Faculty Statistics. One binder on faculty salaries, 1962 - 72; one binder, faculty rosters per department, 1962 - 72. (Box 82)
  - Miscellaneous University Statistics, 4.0
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1951 - 52. (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1953 - 54. (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1955 - 56. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1957 - 58. (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1959 - 60. (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1961 - 62. (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1963 - 64. (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1965 - 66. (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1967 - 68. (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1969 - 70. (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1971 - 72. (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - COMMENCEMENT PROGRAMS: ANNOTATED TO SHOW FACULTY Ph.D. OUTPUT 1973. (Box 83, Folder 12)
- Professional Organizations, 1934-1977; Series IV
  Box 1: American Institute of Electrical Engineers, 1934-49. Although he was a member of this group, and served on its Communications Committee, Dr. Terman was not particularly active in the organization. He was more active in the competing electrical engineering society, the Institute of Radio Engineers. In 1963, the two groups merged, forming the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. the A.I.E.E. folders are arranged alphabetically by subject, and chronologically within each folder.
  Boxes 2-4: American Society for Engineering Education, 1946-77. From the time he became Engineering Dean in 1946 until his appointment as Provost in 1955, Dr. Terman was active in this society, including serving on its board of directors and holding a vice-presidency. During his years as Provost, he had little time to participate in the society, but after his retirement in 1965, became active again. Terman was awarded the Lamme Medal for distinction in engineering education in 1964, and was elected to the A.S.E.E. Hall of Famein 1968. Since 1969, the Hewlett-Packard Company has sponsored the A.S.E.E.'s Frederick Emmons Terman Award presented annually to an outstanding young electrical engineering educator. These files, containing correspondence, minutes, and reports are arranged alphabetically by subject and chronologically within each folder.
  Boxes 5-7: Institute of Electric and Electronics Engineering, 1963-77.
  I.E.E.E. was created in 1964 by the merger of A.I.E.E. and I.R.E. Dr. Terman became active in this group following his retirement in 1965, and was particularly involved in the activities of the Life Member Fund Committee, serving as its chairman for several years. He was also a member of the I.E.E.E. History Committee, and developed active cooperation between the two groups. In addition, he was an editorial advisor to the I.E.E.E. magazine Spectrum from 1973 to 1976. These papers pertain primarily to these three activities. The folders are arranged alphabetically by subject, and chronologically within each folder.
  Boxes 8-16: Institute of Radio Engineers, 1936-52. The I.R.E. was the professional society in which Dr. Terman was most active, serving on many committees. He was elected president in 1941, the first Westerner to hold that office. In the course of his presidency, he restructured-the central offices of the I.R.E., and effected several other significant changes to upgradeadministrative efficiency. The files are arranged alphabetically by subject, and chronologically within each folder.
  Boxes 17-18: Institute for Science and Technology in New Jersey, 1965-69. This organization was formed by a group of corporate executives with major research laboratories in northern New Jersey. They had observed the positive influence of Stanford University on the surrounding high technology companies, and wished to create a similar environment in their area. They formed an industry committee to study the feasibility of creating and underwriting a suitable institution, and engaged Dr. Terman to work out in detail its design and cost. This proposed educational center was never built, because although most of the participating companies agreed with the plans in principle, they did not wish to fully commit themselves financially. The final report that Terman wrote for this project is especially interesting, for it describes in detail his concept of the ideal university-industry liaison. These topically arranged files contain background material and general correspondence; Terman's research and working materials; and his reports.
  Boxes 19-26: Sigma Xi, 1955-76. Sigma Xi is a national honorary society similar to Phi Beta Kappa which emphasizes ability or potential in scientific or technical research. Dr. Terman has been a full member of the Stanford Chapter since 1924, but these files are concerned with his more recent involvement in the society, after his retirement from University administration. He served on the Executive Committee from 1968 to 1976, and was the national president in 1975. Some of his important duties during this time were site visits to evaluate campuses wishing to affiliate with Sigma Xi, and presiding over the installation of new clubs and chapters. The files are arranged alphabetically by subject, and chronologically within each folder.
  - AMERICAN INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL ENGINEERS
    - General Correspondence. 1934 - 36. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence. 1937 - 39. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence. 1941 - 42; 1945. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Basic Sciences, Committee on. 1947 - 49. (Box 1, Folder 4)